MATT FITZPATRICK

T 314.680.1370 matt@50inthe314.com 50inthe314.com hire.50inthe314.com

Marketing professional specializing in media planning through digital channels including search and social media, and traditional channels including outdoor and print. Expertise in strategy development, media buying, asset management, and continuous improvement of campaigns. Develops unique opportunities for brands to cultivate their voice while keeping market and scope in mind. Adapts to changing targets, trends, and tech.

EXPERIENCE

MARKETING COORDINATOR, SAINT LOUIS UNIVERSITY, ST. LOUIS, MO

JANUARY 2014 - PRESENT

- Lead in digital marketing efforts and and media planning for the John Cook School of Business.
- Assist in management and planning of traditional media placements, including print, outdoor, and radio spots.
- Maintain paid ad placements online, including search, banner ads, and retargeting. Develop strategies for long term branding initiatives and short term events. Optimized CPM and CPC while maintaining our target market.
- Launched social ad programs for MBA and Graduate program. Developed placement cycles and defined target metrics for success. Grew ROI year to year, expanded program to include events and other degrees.
- Implemented content marketing strategies and earned-media placements. Organically increased audience 40% and reach 85%. Increased site traffic by 20% with peak increases in social, email, and organic search traffic.
- Manage multiple departments and vendors, work with internal teams and outside agencies to expand efforts.

ACCOUNT MANAGER, THE ABLE FEW, ST. LOUIS, MO NOVEMBER 2012 - NOVEMBER 2013

- Managed internal marketing for the firm, including B2B efforts, social media, and event planning.
- Worked in a continuous release cycle, where many hands were on a single project and concerted contact with the client was required to maintain the expected level of accuracy and excellence.
- Developed business plans and feature release timelines for consumer and business web applications.
- Led in earned media, including features at SXSW, Mashable.com, and other tech events and publications.
- Expanded outreach and followed various paths to connect with new business, including creating responses to RFP's, creating formal proposals for new projects, and attending networking events and one-on-one meetings.

ACCOUNT MANAGER, CTM MEDIA GROUP, ST. LOUIS, MO

OCTOBER 2011 - NOVEMBER 2012

- Managed over 400 traditional and digital advertising placements for an array of clients, from independent restaurants and stores to Fortune 500 companies, athletics and arenas, and major tourism attractions.
- Led expansion in the digital marketing realm, including growth of audience on social media by over 100%, and introduced digital advertising tactics to supplement our traditional marketing techniques.
- Introduced a new hybrid marketing medium to the St. Louis area. Facilitated placement in high end hotels and premium attractions. Increased digital reach in the St. Louis area to 2.5 million visitors annually.
- Created and presented analytical reports and research studies for our clients, showing where their marketing plan succeeded and gave insight on how to improve when needed.

CONSUMER HOSPITALITY REP, ANHEUSER-BUSCH, ST. LOUIS, MO SEPTEMBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2011

- Acted as brand ambassador for guests of Anheuser-Busch at the St. Louis Tour Center.
- Led tours of the brewery complex, educating visitors about the Anheuser-Busch brand and their portfolio.
- Coordinated projects among the staff, kept programs and day to day tasks running smoothly and efficiently.
- Promoted to Guest Service Specialist in fall of 2008.

PROFICIENCIES

- Digital Media Planning- AdSense, AdWords, Google Analytics, most major social media platforms.
- Traditional Media Planning Outdoor, Print, Radio. Have worked with major vendors in the St. Louis area.
- Media Production Expertise in Photoshop, Illustrator & InDesign, proficient in Final Cut Pro.
- Business Microsoft Office Suite, Basecamp and Tableau. Managed 30,000+ contact Salesforce database.

EDUCATION

WEBSTER UNIVERSITY - ST. LOUIS, MO
BA - ADVERTISING AND MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS
SAINT LOUIS UNIVERSITY - ST. LOUIS, MO
MBA - MARKETING

GRADUATED WITH HONORS, MAY 2010

COMPLETION, 2017